A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Joseph H. Boyd, Series 4 FA355
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, Joseph H. Boyd, Series 4
1963-1967
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
Boyd, Joseph H.
FA355
1.31 Cubic Feet 1 standard record storage box.
Biographical/Historical note
Nelson A. Rockefeller served as governor of New York from January 1, 1959, to December 18, 1973. He was the first person elected to four consecutive four-year terms as a state governor.
File Plan note
Former Classification: III 15 4
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Other Finding Aids note
Detailed finding aids for each series of this collection are available:
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Appointments Office (FA353)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Assembly and Senate Memos (FA354)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, James Cannon (FA356)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Affirmative Action (N. Lee Cook) (FA357)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Counsel's Office (FA358)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President (FA359)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Jerry A. Danzig (FA360)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Executive Chamber (FA361)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, 55th Street (FA362)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Issue Books (FA363)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Arthur Massolo (FA364)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Hugh Morrow (FA242)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Office (FA365)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Civil Service Resolutions (Charles H. Palmer) (FA366)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Political Files (FA367)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Press Office (FA368)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Public Relations (FA369)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Departmental Reports (FA370)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, William J. Ronan (FA371)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Speeches (FA372)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Diane Van Wie (FA373)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial (FA374)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Gene Wyckoff (FA375)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports (FA376)
Scope and Contents note
NOTE TO RESEARCHERS
This series contains the office files of Joseph H. Boyd. They document official activities in the execution of his duties as a member of Nelson A. Rockefeller's staff. The actions, decisions, and exchanges of information or points of view documented here occurred in the course of proposing and implementing policies for the Rockefeller administration, political campaigns, and/or Rockefeller's personal activities. However, unless a document is specifically addressed to or from Rockefeller, or is referred to in a document addressed to him, it should not be assumed he saw the document or was aware of its existence or substance. Furthermore, researchers should bear in mind that staff files may contain documents or drafts addressed to Rockefeller that were never shown to him.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This series contains a portion of the files of Joseph H. Boyd. These files primarily document Boyd's tenure as Congressional liaison officer for Governor Rockefeller. During 1967, Boyd maintained an office in Washington, DC, and held regular meetings with members of the New York State Congressional delegation. Almost all of the files pertain to that year, when he routinely spoke with members by telephone and represented the Governor in Washington. Boyd also served as Rockefeller's liaison to the New York State Legislature during this time. Boyd was a member of Governor Rockefeller's staff before as well as after serving in this role. The other files in this series cover his prior service as a Special Assistant to the Governor. Of note are memoranda and correspondence from Henry Kissinger and Edward Teller on such topics as foreign policy, defense spending, and the nuclear test ban treaty before the U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee in 1963 (Folders 42 and 43).
International economic relations; International relations; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; Human rights; Arms control; Affirmative action programs -- New York (State); Civil defense; Arms control -- United States; Political science; Presidential campaigns -- United States; New York (State); Political campaigns -- United States; Legislation -- New York (State); New York (N.Y.); International relations -- United States; Latin America; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Presidential candidates -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Public policy; Public relations; State governments -- United States; United States; Vice-Presidents -- United States; Civil defense -- United States; Civil service; Civil service -- New York (State); Economics; Federal government -- United States; Government policy; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1962
- Air Pollution, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Press release announcing legislation to combat air pollution in the metropolitan New York State region.
- Appalachian Program, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Press release on implementation of Appalachian Program benefiting New York State counties; maps and charts of region.
- Bingham, Jonathan, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Correspondence with the New York Congressman regarding a meeting of New York State Congressional delegation.
- Bohemian Grove, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  NAR notes (typed) of remarks made by Rockefeller in San Francisco, California.
- Button, Daniel, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Correspondence with the New York Congressman.
- Celler, Emanuel, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Correspondence with the New York Congressman regarding Health, Education and Welfare (HEW) funding.
- Conable, B., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Correspondence with the New York Congressman on uban issues.
- Congress, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Press releases, correspondence and memoranda on various issues before Congress.
- Congressional Liaison Office, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Memoranda detailing new role and responsibilities for Boyd; correspondence with New York State Congressional delegation on new office and introducing Boyd in his new role.
- Constitutional Convention, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Memoranda on creation of the "Constitutional Convention Preparation Commission"; suggestions for nominees to commission.
- Daily Sheets, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  To do lists for office staff and daily job responsibilities; notes on telephone conversations.
- Education, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Press release on creation of "Select Committee on the Future of Private and Independent Higher Education in New York State."
- Elementary and Secondary Education Act, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Correspondence and memoranda on debate and issues advanced by federal legislation; "Congressional Record" wherein Act was reported to Congress.
- Elementary and Secondary Education Act, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Federal-State Relations, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Press release, NAR statements on issue.
- Finance Committee, Daily Legislative Committee Reports, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Action memos from the New York State Finance Committee on pending legislation.
- Goodell, Charles, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Hanley, James, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Press release on awarding of Federal grant for park in Onondaga County.
- Healthcare, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Press releases, messages to the Legislature on healthcare issues in New York State.
- Housing Finance Law, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Vote counts, final roll call vote for housing legislation.
- Javits, Jacob, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Correspondence with the New York Senator.
- Kennedy, Robert, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  "Washington Post" article on Senator Kennedy's staff.
- Kupferman, Theodore, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Legislative Bills, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Memoranda, correspondence, bills from New York State Legislature.
- Memos, General, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Memos on congressional delegation and federal issues.
- Mitchell, Donna, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Reports from Washington, D.C. office of the New York State government, located in the Department of Commerce, summarizing federal programs, and legislative issues.
- Mitchell, Donna, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Multer, Abraham, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Correspondence with the New York Congressman on New York State Lottery, federal legislation.
- Narcotics Program, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Press releases, clippings on narcotics issues in New York State, use of Fort Totten (Brooklyn) as a narcotics treatment center.
- NAR Letter to Congress, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Copies of letters to congressional delegation announcing Boyd's appointment.
- New York State Congressional Visits, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Notes on meetings with delegation.
- New York State Programs, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Press releases on various New York State issues.
- Office of Regional Development, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Memoranda and correspondence with Harold Jerry, Director of the Office of Regional Development (ORD) on organization function; press releases, reports on ORD projects.
- Phone Calls, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Record of calls made to members of the New York State Legislature.
- Policy Council (NAR), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Agendas, follow-up items for meetings.
- Reid, Ogden, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Rosenthan, Benjamin, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Phone message from New York Congressman, seeks appointment with NAR to discuss Fort Totten issue.
- Ruge, Daniel, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Correspondence with Ruge, Director of the Washington, D.C., Office of New York State government.
- Smith, Henry, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Correspondence with the New York Congressman on crime control legislation.
- Staff Meetings, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Agendas, summaries of follow-up items, and meeting minutes for NAR staff meetings.
- Staff Meetings, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Agendas, summaries, and meeting minutes for NAR staff meetings.
- Teller, Edward, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Memos to NAR from Teller on defense, foreign policy, nuclear issues.
- Test Ban Treaty, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Correspondence from Henry Kissinger, encloses letter from Edward Teller; status of Treaty in United States Senate, report of committee; Teller correspondence; report on history of treaty; NAR statement, notes, cards for speech on treaty.
- Vacancies, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Memoranda and correspondence on openings in New York State government and recommendations on nominees.
- Wydler, John W., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Correspondence with New York Congressman, meeting with NAR.